Narrator: This is Charlotte Campbell.
She’s twenty-five and she’s a street performer, also known as a busker.
Charlotte plays the guitar and sings on the South Bank in London.
Today, she’s busking near the London Eye.
Charlotte: On a typical day when I’m going busking,
I get the train to Waterloo and I walk to the London Eye.
I start at about eleven o’clock and I play until one.
Then I take a lunch break.
And sometimes I stay until six or seven p.m.,
but in the winter when it gets dark I go home a little earlier.
Narrator: You can find buskers everywhere – on the streets,
in shopping malls,
outside restaurants and in the parks of most big cities.
In some cities, you can also listen to music while you’re on the subway.
Buskers play or sing all kinds of different music – opera, jazz, pop, and folk.
Charlotte: I like music that’s on the radio, Ed Sheeran and things like that,
and some older music from the 60s, like the Beatles.
Narrator: But busking isn’t always easy.
Most big cities are busy and there are lots of buskers,
which means you can’t just play music wherever you like.
Charlotte: You need to get a permit to busk in London,
and pass an audition, but when you do,
there’s a really nice community and busking in London becomes easy.
Narrator: So buskers like Charlotte have to choose an area in the city to sing and play in.
They share this area with other buskers and sometimes they have to wait for the other buskers to finish.
Charlotte lives in Brixton, in South London.
In her apartment, she writes her own songs and practices.
Charlotte: I love writing songs. I love writing my own music.
Narrator: For Charlotte, there are good and bad things about life as a busker.
Charlotte: I like meeting new people and sharing my music with a new audience.
Ba-baa, ba-baa, there’s music on the streets of London
I don’t like it when it gets cold.
Ba-baa, ba-baa, there’s music in my heart
Ba-baa, ba-baa, there’s music on the streets of London
That’s where we are, that’s where we are
Ah-hoo, yeah I get lonely
Ah-hoo, yeah I get cold
Ah-hoo, I get tired, oh so tired
But I’ll never sell my soul.
Ah-hoo, from Piccadilly
Ah-hoo, to Leicester Square
Oh I gave my heart to London
And you’ll always find me there.
Ba-baa, ba-baa, there’s music on the streets of London
Ba-baa, ba-baa, there’s music in my heart
That’s where we are, that’s where we are